Connecticut Soldiers Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Soldiers Collection, Filias J. Plourd Papers.
1943-1946.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Plourd, Filias J.
.25 linear feet.
Corporal Filias J. Plourd of Hartford, CT, served primarily in the post office of the 260th Infantry. A noncombatant over the age of thirty-five, his letters were sent primarily to his brother, Launce.
MSS20050142
Biography
Corporal Filias J. Plourd of Hartford, CT, served primarily in the post office of the 260th Infantry. A noncombatant over the age of thirty-five, his letters were sent primarily to his brother, Launce.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence from Filias "Phil" to his brother, Launce.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence ( 1943-1946 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Plourd, Filias J.
Subjects:
Soldiers--Connecticut--Correspondence.; World War, 1938-1945--Personal narratives--Connecticut.; Hartford (Conn.)--Family and personal papers.; Connecticut==Family and personal papers.; Hartford (Conn.)
Document Types:
Correspondence.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased in November 1996.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1943-1946
  - 1943 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1944 January - February (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1944 March - April (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1944 May - June (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1944 July - September (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1944 October - December (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1945 January - March (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1945 April - July (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1945 August - October (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 10)